<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ansible | Lair of the p-whale]]></title>
  <link href="http://phantomwhale.github.io/blog/categories/ansible/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://phantomwhale.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-21T17:40:08+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://phantomwhale.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ben Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple Server Setup with anSible]]></title>
    <link href="http://phantomwhale.github.io/blog/2013/10/21/simple-server-setup-with-ansible/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-21T16:49:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://phantomwhale.github.io/blog/2013/10/21/simple-server-setup-with-ansible</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So the first topic I intend to write a few posts on is on <a href="http://www.ansibleworks.com/docs/" title="Ansible">Ansible</a>, a system configuration and provisioning tool.</p>

<p>I first was introduced to Ansible at Railscamp 13 (Melbourne, Jun 2013) as a lightweight server provisioning tool. Before then, I had presumed Chef and Puppet were the only players in this space worth watching, but for our small, single-server based deployment stack, using such tools always felt quite heavy.</p>

<p>Up until this point we have mainly stuck with shell scripts and a little manual hackery we documented on a wiki. Of course, documentation is a lie waiting for happen, to paraphrase the <a href="http://rubyrogues.com/079-rr-documenting-code/">Ruby Rogues</a>.</p>

<p>So upcoming I&rsquo;m hoping to post on how we&rsquo;re using Ansible to create our new server, how I&rsquo;ve also been using it on my local machines to get a repeatable development environment installed and there is also a presentation I am working on to introduce the topic to a wider audience.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll end this post with a link to an e-book by <a href="http://mattjaynes.com/">Matt Jaynes</a> that I found quite helpful when trying to understand how Ansible fits into the server provisioning &ldquo;space&rdquo; in general. It&rsquo;s called <a href="http://devopsu.com/books/taste-test-puppet-chef-salt-stack-ansible.html">Taste Test</a> and covers using Puppet, Chef, Salt and, of course, Ansible to configure a simple server setup.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
